<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shell on Aum&#39;s blogging site</title>
    <link>https://aumpauskar.github.io/blog/tags/shell/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Shell on Aum&#39;s blogging site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 15:34:19 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://aumpauskar.github.io/blog/tags/shell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lab expts sem 6</title>
      <link>https://aumpauskar.github.io/blog/posts/misc/lab_expts_sem_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 15:34:19 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aumpauskar.github.io/blog/posts/misc/lab_expts_sem_6/</guid>
      <description>Lab expts sem 6 AIML TW1 - DFID 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 49 50 51 52 from collections import defaultdict class Graph: def __init__(self, vertices): self.V = vertices self.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Windows scripts with powershell and cmd</title>
      <link>https://aumpauskar.github.io/blog/posts/os/windows_scripts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 22:42:51 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aumpauskar.github.io/blog/posts/os/windows_scripts/</guid>
      <description>Windows prompts PowerShell PowerShell is a command-line shell and scripting language built on the .NET Framework. It is the successor to the Command Prompt. Commands are called cmdlets and are written in the form Verb-Noun. For example, Get-ChildItem lists the contents of a directory. There are a few aliases for common commands, such as ls for Get-ChildItem and rm for Remove-Item.&#xA;Write-Output: Prints a line in the shell New-Item: Creates a new file within the same directory Get-Content: Reads the contents of a file Set-Content: Writes the contents of a file Remove-Item: Deletes a file Get-ChildItem: Lists the contents of a directory Command Alias Description Write-Output echo Prints a line in the shell New-Item touch Creates a new file within the same directory Get-Content type Reads the contents of a file Set-Content echo Writes the contents of a file Remove-Item del Deletes a file Get-ChildItem dir Lists the contents of a directory CMD echo &amp;lt;line&amp;gt;: Prints a line in the shell type &amp;lt;file&amp;gt;: Reads the contents of a file file operations copy &amp;lt;source&amp;gt; &amp;lt;target&amp;gt;: Copies a file move &amp;lt;source&amp;gt; &amp;lt;target&amp;gt;: Moves a file del &amp;lt;file&amp;gt;: Deletes a file dir: Lists the contents of a directory cd commands: required to change the current directory cd &amp;lt;dir&amp;gt;: Changes the current directory cd .</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linux</title>
      <link>https://aumpauskar.github.io/blog/posts/os/linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 12:52:03 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aumpauskar.github.io/blog/posts/os/linux/</guid>
      <description>Linux/UNIX shell commands The UNIX shell is a command-line interface made for interacting with the OS. There are various commands to execute this.&#xA;Note: The current documentaiton is based on Ububtu and similar debian bases operating systems.&#xA;File systems The linux file system is a tree structure with the root directory at the top. The root directory is denoted by /. The directories are separated by / and the files are separated by .</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
