<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Os on Aum&#39;s blogging site</title>
    <link>https://aumpauskar.github.io/blog/tags/os/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Os on Aum&#39;s blogging site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 21:32:54 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://aumpauskar.github.io/blog/tags/os/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Docker</title>
      <link>https://aumpauskar.github.io/blog/posts/web/docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 21:32:54 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aumpauskar.github.io/blog/posts/web/docker/</guid>
      <description>Docker What is docker Docker is a platform for developers and sysadmins to develop, deploy, and run applications with containers. The use of Linux containers to deploy applications is called containerization. Containers are not new, but their use for easily deploying applications is.&#xA;Why docker Consistency: Docker provides a consistent environment for your application from development all the way through production. Isolation: Docker containers are completely isolated. This means that your application will run the same way no matter where it is deployed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operating systems</title>
      <link>https://aumpauskar.github.io/blog/posts/os/os/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 17:09:25 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aumpauskar.github.io/blog/posts/os/os/</guid>
      <description>Operating systems Bases of an operating system Execute user programs and make solving user problems easier Make the computer system convenient to use Use the computer hardware in an efficient manner A computer system can be divided roughly into four components: the hardware, the operating system, the application programs, and the users.&#xA;Use of an operating system The operating system is responsible for the following activities in connection with process management Process creation and deletion Process suspension and resumption Provision of mechanisms for process synchronization Provision of mechanisms for process communication Provision of mechanisms for deadlock handling Operating systems is a resource allocator and it is a control program.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
