<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Aum&#39;s blogging site</title>
    <link>http://aumpauskar.site/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Aum&#39;s blogging site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 22:20:04 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://aumpauskar.site/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Motor_encoder</title>
      <link>http://aumpauskar.site/blog/posts/projects/motor_encoder/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 22:20:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aumpauskar.site/blog/posts/projects/motor_encoder/</guid>
      <description>Motor Encoder Components Arduino Uno 4x4 Keypad I2C LCD DC Motor with encoder Connections pending
Code 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 49 50 51 52 53 54 55 56 57 58 59 60 61 62 63 64 65 66 67 68 69 70 71 72 73 74 75 76 77 78 79 80 81 82 83 84 85 86 87 88 89 90 91 92 93 94 95 96 97 98 99 100 101 102 103 104 105 106 107 108 109 110 111 112 // ---------- // keypad setup #include &amp;lt;Keypad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arm</title>
      <link>http://aumpauskar.site/blog/posts/iot/arm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 12:59:45 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aumpauskar.site/blog/posts/iot/arm/</guid>
      <description>A basic introduction to ARM and how to run ARM IC within a simulator - LPC2148</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Html Web</title>
      <link>http://aumpauskar.site/blog/posts/web/html-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 09:21:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aumpauskar.site/blog/posts/web/html-web/</guid>
      <description>Web notes FYI CSA: Client server architecture A web can be two tier, three tier, n tier having different applets for different purposes HTML: Hypertext markup lang, CSS: Cascading stylesheet, JS: Javascript P2P: Peer to peer architecture DOM: Document Object Model (DOM) is a file model wherein all the files are shown in a multiinterface structural model Tree stucture: A tree structure is a model where the start point is a single node but as we go down the model the number of nodess increase just like a tree.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Static Site Generators</title>
      <link>http://aumpauskar.site/blog/posts/web/static-site-generators/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 09:19:25 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aumpauskar.site/blog/posts/web/static-site-generators/</guid>
      <description>Static site generators A short guide on how this site was created using hugo.
Introduction There are multiple ways of creating of a website, if for example a simple site needs to be created with minimal content and updates a static site might be adequate, however if the site needs a frontend, backend and a database then a dynamic site is required. If the content is the only thing that matters and the content needs to be updated regularly then a static site generator is required.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sql</title>
      <link>http://aumpauskar.site/blog/posts/dbms/sql/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 14:41:25 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aumpauskar.site/blog/posts/dbms/sql/</guid>
      <description>Sql documentation Installation The installation and usage of MySQL can be done in many ways; one is to install WAMP/XAMPP server and using SQL through it another is to use an online sql emulator, the best way is to use a MySQL server.
Getting started with MySQL All the operations in SQL can be classified into 3 types DDL: Data definition language includes operation like create, alter, drop DML: Data manipulation language includes operation like select, insert, update, delete DCL: Data control language includes operations like commit, rollback, grant, revoke</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dsabasics</title>
      <link>http://aumpauskar.site/blog/posts/dsa/dsabasics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 10:38:34 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aumpauskar.site/blog/posts/dsa/dsabasics/</guid>
      <description>A complete guide ds Termwork 1 - Infix evaluation Algorithm Create an empty stack (operandStack) to store operands and an empty stack (operatorStack) to store operators. Initialize a variable (result) to store the final output Iterate through each character of the infix expression. If the current character is an operand, add it to the operandStack. If the current character is an operator, pop operators from operatorStack and add them to operandStack until an operator with lower precedence is found.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Embeddedc</title>
      <link>http://aumpauskar.site/blog/posts/iot/embeddedc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 10:37:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aumpauskar.site/blog/posts/iot/embeddedc/</guid>
      <description>Embedded C Embedded C is used in embedded systems and iot deviced such as Arduino and mico IC&amp;rsquo;s. To emulate this we can use Keil, however this can be only run on Windows, to run this on linux based distros use wine.
Procedure to run The following are the steps to run a code on Keil Note: Here we are working on intel 8051AH microcontroller
Install and run keil If you are on a windows system you can run the exe file locally, if you are on a linux machine you can run keil through wine and it will function just like you are running it on windows natively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arduino</title>
      <link>http://aumpauskar.site/blog/posts/iot/arduino/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 10:37:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aumpauskar.site/blog/posts/iot/arduino/</guid>
      <description>Arduino 14 IO, 6//
ESP 8266 wifi
Sketch - name of the program Setup - IO setup Loop - while loop DHT 11 sol moisture SR04 ultrasonic HC05 bluetooth ESP 01 wifi
Q. LED blink 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 const int ledVar = 13; void setup() { pinMode(ledVar, OUTPUT); } void loop() { digitalWrite(ledVar, HIGH); delay(1000); digitalWrite(ledVar, LOW); delay(1000); } Q. Interface dht 11 with arduino uno and display humidity and temperature on serial monitor 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 #include &amp;lt;dht.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Javafull</title>
      <link>http://aumpauskar.site/blog/posts/java/javafull/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 10:35:36 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aumpauskar.site/blog/posts/java/javafull/</guid>
      <description>Java tutorial Java is a cross platform compiled language that uses jvm (java virtual machine) that can be used in any machine no matter the hardware or software, provided the machine supports jvm
FYI The object class is the root of all classes Data can be gatered with the scanner method in the java library but cannot cater charecter type data with the standard library. Those can be gathered by sc = next().</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualenv</title>
      <link>http://aumpauskar.site/blog/posts/python/virtualenv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 10:34:31 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aumpauskar.site/blog/posts/python/virtualenv/</guid>
      <description>Python virtual environment Python virtual environemt is a program that aids in creating a serperate virtual environment for each project
Requiremnets Python 3 Pip Steps Installing virtual environemnt package 1 pip install virtualenv Creating virtual environent Windows - cmd/powershell
1 py -m venv {your_env_name} Linux
1 python3 -m venv myworld Activating virtual environemt Windows - cmd
1 myworld\Scripts\activate.bat Windows - powershell
1 myworld\Scripts\activate.ps1 Linux
1 source myworld/bin/activate Downloading required packages 1 py -m pip install {required_package} </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Packages</title>
      <link>http://aumpauskar.site/blog/posts/python/packages/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 10:08:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aumpauskar.site/blog/posts/python/packages/</guid>
      <description>Chapter summary - Unit 5 Packages: How to build a GUI Program: Create a GUI that handles an event, more skills for working with components; Numpy Basics: Arrays and Vectorized Computation: Creating ndarrays, Data Types for ndarrays, Operations between Arrays and Scalars, Basic Indexing and Slicing, Indexing with slices, Boolean Indexing, Transposing Arrays and Swapping Axes; Getting started with Pandas: Introduction to Pandas Data Structures, Summarizing and Computing Descriptive Statistics, Handling missing data; Plotting and Visualization: A Brief matplotlib API Primer, Plotting Functions in panda</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oops</title>
      <link>http://aumpauskar.site/blog/posts/python/oops/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 10:07:41 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aumpauskar.site/blog/posts/python/oops/</guid>
      <description>Chapter summary - Unit 4 Object Oriented Programming: Define and use your own classes: An introduction to classes and objects, define a class, object composition, encapsulation; Inheritance: Inheritance, override object methods; Design an object oriented program: Techniques for object-oriented design Text Book 1 – Chapters 14,15,16
Creating your own class A class can be created in python by using the class keyword
1 2 class MyClass: x = 5 This creates a blueprint for the objects to be defined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lists</title>
      <link>http://aumpauskar.site/blog/posts/python/lists/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 10:07:18 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aumpauskar.site/blog/posts/python/lists/</guid>
      <description>Chapter summary - Unit 2 Higher Data Constructs: Lists and tuples: Basic skills for working with lists, list of lists, more skills for working with lists, tuples; Dictionaries: get started with dictionaries, more skills for working with dictionaries; Strings: Basic skills for working with strings, split and join strings; Dates and times: get started with dates and times Text Book 1 – Chapters 6,12,10,11
Datatypes - complex Lists: A list is a mutable datatype in which all the elements are indexed from 0 to n 1 myList = [5,7,3,7] Tuples: A tuple is an immutable datatype in which all the elements are indexed from 0 to n 1 myTuple = (6,2,5,5) Dictionaries: A dictionary is a complex mutable datatype in which the elements are indexed upon the user&amp;rsquo;s needs, this is called the key value pairs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data</title>
      <link>http://aumpauskar.site/blog/posts/python/data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 10:06:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aumpauskar.site/blog/posts/python/data/</guid>
      <description>Chapter summary - Unit 3 File I/O: An introduction to file I/O, test files, CSV files, binary files; Exception Handling: handle a single exception, handle multiple exceptions, Two more skills; Work with a database: An introduction to relational databases, SQL statements for data manipulation, SQLite Manager to work with a database, use Python to work with a database
File write modes &amp;ldquo;x&amp;rdquo; - Create - will create a file, returns an error if the file exist &amp;ldquo;a&amp;rdquo; - Append - will create a file if the specified file does not exist &amp;ldquo;w&amp;rdquo; - Write - will create a file if the specified file does not exist 1 f = open(&amp;#34;myfile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basics</title>
      <link>http://aumpauskar.site/blog/posts/python/basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 10:05:13 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aumpauskar.site/blog/posts/python/basics/</guid>
      <description>Basics of python</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Post</title>
      <link>http://aumpauskar.site/blog/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 09:46:38 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aumpauskar.site/blog/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>Hello World This is my first post
1 print(&amp;#34;Hello World&amp;#34;) </description>
    </item>
    
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
