<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>React on Aum&#39;s blogging site</title>
    <link>https://aumpauskar.github.io/blog/tags/react/</link>
    <description>Recent content in React on Aum&#39;s blogging site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 16:36:16 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://aumpauskar.github.io/blog/tags/react/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mern tutorial</title>
      <link>https://aumpauskar.github.io/blog/posts/web/mern/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 16:36:16 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aumpauskar.github.io/blog/posts/web/mern/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;mern-stack-tutorial&#34;&gt;MERN Stack Tutorial&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;01-running-express-js&#34;&gt;01-Running express js&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;preface&#34;&gt;Preface&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Express is a minimal and flexible Node.js web application framework that provides a robust set of features for web and mobile applications. It is an open-source framework developed and maintained by the Node.js foundation. It is designed for building web applications and APIs. It is the standard server framework for Node.js.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before starting with express js, ensure that you have node.js, npm and a code editor installed on your system. The installation of node.js and npm can be verified by running the following commands in the terminal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building websites with React</title>
      <link>https://aumpauskar.github.io/blog/posts/web/react/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 09:20:47 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aumpauskar.github.io/blog/posts/web/react/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;react-tutorial&#34;&gt;React tutorial&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-the-tutorial&#34;&gt;About the tutorial&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This short note is based and created assuming you are using a Linux (debian/ubuntu) system, most of the commands will run on other systems like Windows and Mac as well but may require some changes. In case you need to follow along and using a Windows system, you can use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/wsl/install-win10&#34;&gt;Windows Subsystem for Linux&lt;/a&gt; to run the commands.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;installing-react&#34;&gt;Installing react&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In order to install react, node and npm are required. To install node and npm, run the following command:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Web technologies - basic HTML/CSS/JS</title>
      <link>https://aumpauskar.github.io/blog/posts/web/html-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 09:21:22 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aumpauskar.github.io/blog/posts/web/html-web/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;web-notes&#34;&gt;Web notes&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;fyi&#34;&gt;FYI&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;CSA: Client server architecture&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A web can be two tier, three tier, n tier having different applets for different purposes&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;HTML: Hypertext markup lang, CSS: Cascading stylesheet, JS: Javascript&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;P2P: Peer to peer architecture&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;DOM: Document Object Model (DOM) is a file model wherein all the files are shown in a multiinterface structural model&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tree stucture: A tree structure is a model where the start point is a single node but as we go down the model the number of nodess increase just like a tree.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;misc&#34;&gt;Misc&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;amp;npsp: singlewhitespace&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;basics&#34;&gt;Basics&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;structure-of-a-html-document&#34;&gt;Structure of a HTML document&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A HTML document contents many tags called as elements. These elements are crutial in making a HTML document. This is the common structure of an HTML document.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Static site generators with Hugo</title>
      <link>https://aumpauskar.github.io/blog/posts/web/static-site-generators/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 09:19:25 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aumpauskar.github.io/blog/posts/web/static-site-generators/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;static-site-generators&#34;&gt;Static site generators&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A short guide on how this site was created using hugo.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are multiple ways of creating of a website, if for example a simple site needs to be created with minimal content and updates a &lt;strong&gt;static site&lt;/strong&gt; might be adequate, however if the site needs a frontend, backend and a database then a &lt;strong&gt;dynamic site&lt;/strong&gt; is required. If the content is the only thing that matters and the content needs to be updated regularly then a static site generator is required. Multiple static site generators are avalable as open source projects, one of them is &lt;strong&gt;jeckyll&lt;/strong&gt; from github and the other is &lt;strong&gt;hugo&lt;/strong&gt; that is optimized for minmal loadtime.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
